

📕+1 210-609-8772 | 💌 caasilemroh@gmail.com | 🧥 isaachormel.com | 🖸 https://github.com/rewrite123 | 🛅 https://www.linkedin.com/in/isaac-hormel/

"It's hard to beat a person who never gives up"

# Summary \_\_\_\_

Dedicated employee with over four years of professional experience as a fullstack developer specializing in MERN technologies. Lead projects and consulted on teams to ensure overall success and fulfill my responsibilities. I have a passion for Linux (Ubuntu), open source software, and hardware tinkering. Interested in devising solutions to challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools as the need arises.

# **Technologies**\_

- NodeJS
- TypeScript
- JavaScript
- Git
- RxJS
- React
- Angular
- Webpack

- Rollup
- Babel
- MaterialUI
- Bootstrap
- Tailwind CSS
- SASS/SCSS
- HTML/CSS/JS
- ExpressJS

- RESTful API
- Docker
- NGINX
- MySQL
- PostgreSQL
- MongoDB
- ElasticSearch
- Prisma

- Sequelize
- AWS
- Heroku
- Linux (Ubuntu)
- · SSH
- Ansible
- Kubernetes
- Figma

# Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

# **Trade Log**

FULLSTACK DEVELOPER June 2023 - current

- Designed and implemented a trade logging platform hosted on Digital Ocean.
- Created a robust trade logging CRM using React to import existing trades as a CSV, add new or edit old trades.

#### **Second Street**

FULLSTACK DEVELOPER Apr. 2023 - June 2023

- Created a rental website for rehersal studios that integrated with Stripe for payment.
- Designed and implemented an admin dashboard and booking flow for rehersal building owners.

### **Utopia Compression**

FRONTEND DEVELOPER Feb. 2023 - Apr. 2023

- Created an Electron app using React as a Navy Interface Development Consultant.
- Collaborated on the design and function of desktop applications.

### **Sports Vet**

MOBILE & BACKEND DEVELOPER Oct. 2022 - Jan. 2023

- Utilized React Native to create and sideload an app for video annotation pruposes.
- Created APIs for storing video and maintaining authorization tokens across devices.

## **ThrivSports**

SR. FULLSTACK DEVELOPER & PROJECT LEAD

Sep. 2019 - Sep. 2022 full/part

- Lead backend engineer for new TypeScript API for internal use and for use with partners.
- Consulted on Elastic Search API for fast Map requests and location data.
- Responsible for React CRM portal for coaches and coach managers.
- Project lead for React search marketplace with Google Maps for coach location services.
- Project lead for React coach booking applet. An applet showcasing services coaches offer and their availabilities that are open for purchase.
- Project lead for React coach profile applet. An applet that showed coach bio, certifications, events, and affiliation.

#### **BatRX**

LEAD FRONTEND DEVELOPER Mar. 2020 - Feb. 2021

- Lead frontend developer for React SPA for data entry and submission with the ability to see and sort data with chartJS.
- Consulted on backend APIs and use with Swagger documentation.

# Personal Projects \_\_\_\_\_

#### isaachormel.com

FULLSTACK DEVELOPER Sep. 2022 - current

- Created and currently manage isaachormel.com, a personal site for clients to learn more about me.
- Created blogging software, art assets and designs with Figma, and deployment with AWS.

#### **ESP32 admin dashboard**

C Hardware Programing Mar. 2020

- A small ESP32 project to control robotic switches over a wifi TCP connection.
- Porting over Marauder software with use with the popular hacking tool Flipper to PlatformIO for use on Linux and OSX.

# **Raspberry Pi Cluster**

Devops July 2020

• Set up raspberry pi 3 Bs in a cluster managed with Kubernetes and Docker to improve my knowledge of the technologies.

#### Etsy

DIGITAL ARTIST Jan. 2021 - current

- Over the years I have created a varitable stockpile of art assets created with Figma which I now sell on Etsy.
- Art assets for sale center around office supplies and programming needs.

## **Education**

### **University of Texas at El Paso**

El Paso, Tx

COMPUTER SCIENCE

July 2017 - Mar. 2018

• Attended UTEP briefly in pursuit of a computer science degree, but ultimately dropped out in favor of a coding bootcamp and fulltime employment in IT.

# **University of Texas at Austin Coding Boot Camp**

Austin, Tx

COMPUTER SCIENCE

Aug. 2018 - Jan. 2019

- Attended the UTA Coding Boot Camp where I learned about frontend technologies like React and Ember, databases, and backend technologies like ExpressJS and Prisma.
- Finished the course with an overall grade of A-